Why did you protect me?
Because. I don't have a reason.
I'm the one who killed your comrade.
I'm the one who bludgeoned the guard.
Falco didn't do it. Kill me, not him.
We won't kill you.
But you want to, don't you?
I don't want to kill you.
Kill this, kill that...
It's all you think about.
Just like someone I know.
Er--
"Savagery"
I just wanna talk. Conflict isn't
necessary to solve Eldia's problems.
Hange and the others are fine.
We're just moving them.
Eren, we're the ones who wanted to talk.
What made you go attack
Marley all on your own?
Did Zeke and Yelena really
talk you into joining them?
I am free.
Huh?
The things I do and choices I make
are all decided by my own free will.
So your actions after
meeting Yelena were all you?
Yes.
No, you're being manipulated!
You wouldn't get kids and innocents
involved, even if they were enemies!
Plus, I know you care
about us more than anyone!
Don't you? The reason you
saved me in the cabin...
The reason you gave me this
scarf... is because you're kind--
I said, "Keep your hands on the table."
I spoke with Zeke in Liberio,
brother to brother.
Zeke knows more about Titans
than even Marley does.
Armin, aren't you still visiting Annie?
Do you think that's your own free will?
Wh-What?
If memories are what shape people,
a part of you is Bertholdt now.
Within you is an enemy
with feelings for another enemy.
Armin... Bertholdt has got into your head.
You're the one manipulated by the enemy.
Eren, what are--?
You, too, Mikasa.
Huh?
The Ackermanns were intentionally
designed to protect Eldia's King.
Back then, faced with a life-or-death
situation, you heard my order:
"Fight."
In that moment, instincts
awoke from within you.
By mistake, you thought I was
the host you had to protect.
No...
No? No, what?
It wasn't... a mistake.
It's because it was you, Eren!
I became strong because of you!
Ackermanns with awakened powers
apparently get sudden headaches.
It happens when their old self resists
being forced to protect their host.
Sound familiar?
No.
I'm saying...
No, I...
Your family was made to forget who
they are and live only to protect.
In other words, slaves.
Enough, Eren!
Do you know who I hate more than anyone?
Those who aren't free. Just like livestock.
Eren!
Just seeing you has always pissed me
off so much, and now I finally know why.
I can't stand the sight of a slave
who obeys orders without question.
Ever since I was little...
...Mikasa, I've hated you.
Eren! How could you say that to--?
Mikasa?
Your entire life has been dictated
by your Ackermann blood.
N-No!
It's all you really are.
Jaeger!
I'm all right.
Hey, Armin. You and I have
never fought before, have we?
Do you know why?
--Because it's not even close to a fair fight!
--Stop.
Please, stop.
Like I said, if you guys tell us where
Zeke is, there's no need for us to fight.
Come along and behave. Take 'em.
Yes, sir.
The kid who killed Sasha, too.
Is that it? Is that all you came to say?
That you wanted freedom
just so you could hurt Mikasa?
Tell me: Who's the slave
that bows to a bastard again?
Who you calling a slave? Let's go.
Where?
To where it all started--Shiganshina.
It's not even funny.
There's another shithead we should have eaten.
What do you mean?
We'll give the Beast to someone else.
We'll make one of the Jaegerists
into a Titan and have them eat Zeke.
I can't tell if he's manipulating Eren,
but their party's over if they lose Zeke.
Go tell that to Pyxis, got it?
You're serious, Captain?
The old man will come around
once I chop Zeke's limbs off.
Enjoying your book?
I am, for one I've read seven times.
You've been eavesdropping more than reading.
Can you blame me when
I've read it this much?
By the way, is there any wine left?
Not a single drop left.
We've been here a month.
Good grief.
You sure know how to torture someone.
Just read your book.
Roger that, boss.
I'm gonna chop him up
no matter what Pyxis says.
There're 30 fully-armed soldiers
waiting in the forest above.
Even if he becomes the Beast,
there's no way he escapes.
That bearded shit was our enemy after all.
And now that we know it,
he doesn't deserve to have limbs.
It took long enough.
Erwin, I'll finally uphold
the promise I made to you.
There was meaning in your deaths.
And at long last, I'll prove it.
Huh?
Hey...
"Spinal Fluid Wine: After consuming the spinal
fluid and hearing Zeke Yaeger's 'scream,'
Subjects of Ymir will turn into Pure Titans.
It has proven to be an effective weapon."
What was that?
My body went numb.
--Yeah!
--Me, too!
Huh? I didn't feel a thing.
What's wrong?
Felt like I got zapped by electricity.
You don't think--?!
Zeke's done it, hasn't he?
This is goodbye, Captain.
You care about your subordinates.
You're not gonna slice them up
just 'cuz they've grown a bit, are you?
Wine? Why bring wine on a mission?
Captain! This is the rare Marleyan
stuff only MPs get to drink!
Don't we deserve some?
We've got tea.
Captain!
Gimme a break.
Fine. Bring it.
Dammit!
Zeke's spinal fluid was
in the wine?! Since when?!
Not a single person froze up! Was it all a lie?!
Shit, they're fast! How do they move
like that?! Is that Zeke's doing, too?!
Varis!
Are you in there somewhere...
...you guys?
Farewell. In the end,
we couldn't trust one another.
All the world's might
will soon fall upon this island.
You have no idea what that means.
You guys thought you
had power... time... choices.
Not realizing you had none of those,
Levi, was your biggest mistake.
Still, even if I explained my intentions,
you wouldn't understand.
Right, Eren?
Only you and I do.
Once I escape this forest,
that's where you'll be.
I hope you remember where and when
we're supposed to meet, Eren.
Hmm?
Go!
What the hell, dammit?! Again?!
Where are you?!
Where'd you go, Levi?!
There you are!
What happened to your lovely buddies?!
Don't tell me you killed 'em all!
The poor things!
Branches?!
You're looking desperate, hairball!
All you had to do was read your damn book.
What gave you the idea
that you could escape from me?
Did you think I wouldn't kill my comrades
if they turned into Titans?
You don't have a damn clue
how many comrades we've killed!
Hi there, Beardy.
Damn. You stink and you're filthy,
you ugly piece of shit.
Well, no worries,
'cuz I'm not gonna kill you... yet.
As you know, after Premier Zachary was killed,
the situation within the walls
has become unstable.
However, this doesn't concern you cadets.
Which is why the 109th Cadet Corps
will be training to defend
Shiganshina from Titan attack!
You hear me?!
Y-Yes, sir!
Why do we care how to cut a Titan's nape?
Not like they'll attack again.
Our enemies are people now.
My old man thinks we should be training
with firearms and form an Eldian army.
The times have changed,
yet Commandant Shadis is stuck in the past.
Eldia's only hope is for
the Jaegerists to seize full control.
Surma, he can hear you!
Isn't that what everyone's thinking?
Everyone wants Eren Jaeger to lead Eldia.
We need a leader capable
of making tough decisions.
Wha--?! Hange?!
Long time no see, Commandant.
Just so you know, this branch
is under new management.
We "Jaegerists" are the ones in charge now.
From now on, you take orders from us.
The Jaegerists...
Looks like you finally figured it out, Floch.
Unless you point guns at people,
nobody cares what your little gang
of asswipes says, and that's a fact.
Floch!
I missed.
I thought shooting his foot
might speed things up.
Speed what up?
No, it has nothing to do with you.
We have little need for
hard-headed geezers like you.
From now on, this is your time, cadets!
We Jaegerists have sworn to give our
hearts to save Eldia from this crisis!
Not for the sake of our obsolete military,
but for the people of this island!
By obeying the military's archaic mindset,
you're allowing us to be trampled
by enemies from outside!
Therefore, I ask you: Who are you?!
Someone who wants to live
alongside our leader, Eren Jaeger?!
Or someone who will die alongside
Keith Shadis and his antiquated ways?!
For the sake of Eldia's future,
we give our hearts!
Good! Now show me your resolve!
Beat Commandant Shadis
till he can't stand anymore!
Huh?
He represents the old ways that
must be driven out! Now, do it!
Those who can't go to prison!
That's enough, Floch! This is ridiculous!
Hange!
No matter how many of these tots
there are, they're no match for me!
Well done. We're delighted to welcome you all.
Now, could you guide us
to where Zeke's being held?
Commander Hange.
Hey, let's go.
You awake?
Hey, wait. Don't move.
There's a wire around your neck
attached to the Thunder Spear fuse.
Squirm too much and you'll be
blown in half or worse.
Bet you wish you were dead right now.
Not that I sympathize.
You toyed with the lives of my comrades.
Tell me: Was whimpering while covered
in shit part of your master plan?!
Shut up! Unless I slice you to bits,
you'll turn into a Titan again!
Where... are... my glasses?
Huh? Who cares?
You won't be needing 'em anymore.
Nice one, Zeke!
You're getting good at throwing!
Ever thought about playing baseball?
I can't, Mr. Ksaver...
I... have a mission.
One remembers long-missed faces
and distant memories.
Likewise, what must be
done to achieve one's mission.
Next episode: "Sole Salvation."